Personal Data Prof. Roberto Togneri

The University of Western Australia, Electrical Eng., Perth

Web Page and Research Profile

Employment

2013-today The University of Western Australia, Professor

Audio-Visual Signal Processing and Recognition

The University of Western Australia, Senior Lecturer 1997-2013

Speech Signal Processing and Recognition

1988-1997 The University of Western Australia, Lecturer

Signal and Network Information Systems

Education

1989 PhD The University of Western Australia 1985 BE (Hons) The University of Western Australia

Professional Associations

Senior Member of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) Member of the Australian Speech Science and Technology Association (ASSTA) Member of the International Speech Communication Association (ISCA)

Short Biography

Professor Roberto Togneri received the B.E. degree in 1985, and the Ph.D degree in 1989 both from the University of Western Australia. He joined the School of Electrical, Electronic and Computer Engineering at The University of Western Australia in 1988, where he is now currently an Associate Professor. Professor Togneri leads the Signal Processing and Recognition Lab and his research activities in signal processing and pattern recognition include: feature extraction and enhancement of audio signals, statistical and neural network models for speech and speaker recognition, audio-visual recognition and biometrics, and related aspects of language modelling and understanding. He has published over 130 refereed journal and conference papers in the areas of signal processing and recognition, the chief investigator on three Australian Research Council Discovery Project research grants since 2009, and is currently an Associate Editor for IEEE Signal Processing Magazine Lecture Notes and IEEE Transactions on Speech, Audio and Language Processing.

Research Grants Awarded

2015-	ARC	Enhanced Visibility and Increased Productivity
	DP150102405	
2012-	NeCTAR	VL222: Above and Beyond Speech, Language and Music: A Virtual Lab for Human
2014	Virtual Laboratory	Communication Science (HCS vLab)
2011-	ARC	Development of a three dimensional audio-visual next generation speech
2016	DP11010366	recognition system
2010-	ARC	Robust speech recognition in realistic hostile environments
2015	DP1096348	
2010-	ARC	The Big Australian Speech Corpus: An audio-visual speech corpus of Australian
2015	LE100100211	English

Selected Research Publications

- 1. S.H. Khan, M. Bennamoun, F. Sohel, R. Togneri, "Automatic Shadow Detection and Removal from a Single Image", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, Vol. 38, No. 3, March 2016, pp 431-446.
- C. Sui, R. Togneri, M. Bennamoun, "Listening by Eyes: Towards a Practical Visual Speech Recognition System Using Deep Boltzmann Machines", Proceedings of ICCV2015, December 2015, Santiago, Chile, accepted September 2015.
- 3. M.R. Alam, M. Bennamoun, R. Togneri, F. Sohel, "A Deep Neural Network for Audio-Visual Person Recognition", Proceedings of BTAS2015, September 2015, Arlington, USA.
 4. I. Jafari, R. Togneri, S. Nordholm, "On the Use of the Watson Mixture Model for Clustering-Based Under-Determined Blind Source
- Separation", Proceedings of InterSpeech2014, September 2014, Singapore, pp. 988-992.
- 5. R. Togneri, D. Pullella, "An Overview of Speaker Identification: Accuracy and Robustness Issues", IEEE Circuits and Systems Magazine, Vol. 11, No. 2, 2nd Quarter 2011, pp. 23-61.
- 6. M. Kuhne, R. Togneri, S. Nordholm, "A New Evidence Model for Missing Data Speech Recognition with Applications in Reverberant Multi-source Environments", IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing, Vol. 19, No. 2, February 2011, pp.
- 7. I. Naseem, R. Togneri, M. Bennamoun, "Linear Regression for Face Recognition", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, Vol. 32, No. 11, November 2010, pp. 2106-2112.

Roberto Togneri CV

